Oleg Vinokurov Sherman Oaks, Ca 91401 (213) 304-6153 OlegVinokurov@hotmail.com

OVERVIEW

Senior-level Full-Stack Software Architect/ Engineer with over fifteen years of experience in a broad range of technologies. Key participant and leader in all phases of a development life cycle for a number of systems. Technical expertise and knowledge in translating organizational requirements into detailed business solutions.

SKILLS

- Excellent verbal and written skills.
- Effective strategic thinker and a team player.

Programming Languages: C#, PHP, Python, Java, Visual Basic, C, C++, SQL, PL/SQL, HTML,

CFML, DHTML, CSS, XML, UML, VBScript, & JavaScript. DBMS: ORACLE, MySQL, MS SQL Server and MS Access.

Operation Systems: Dos, Windows, UNIX, and Mac OS.

Web & Cloud: Web Services (AWS Lambda) and Microsoft Azure

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

04/2016-Present

Santa Monica, California

Wells Fargo Capital Finance

- Involved in Software Development Life Cycle like Requirement Analysis, Design, Implementation and Testing.
- Followed Agile methodology with daily scrum meetings and providing user story updates
 Worked with JIRA as an ALM tool for the central view for user stories and the bug
 tracking.
- Extensively involved in coding business logic and UI.
- Using the REST principles.
- Implementing the data access layer using Entity Framework Code First approach and writing queries using LINQ to Entity for data retrieval.
- Developed various stored procedures for the data retrieval from the database and generating different reports.

Environment: C#, Web Service, ASP.NET, MVC, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Python, Golang, Angular 1,5 and 6 AJAX, JSON, XML, jQuery, HTML5.

1/2013-08/2016

CBS Sports

Los Angeles, California

Architected and Developed Mobile Web-based application "Fantasy Games". This application is close to a standard fantasy basketball league, but with special care taken on the scoring system and league rules. http://www.cbssports.com/mobile - Brackets

Environment: C Sharp(C#), Razor, Web Service, ASP.NET, MVC, Framework 4.0, LINQ, Node.js, Python, JavaScript, BackBone.js, AngularJS, TypeScript, AJAX, JSON, XML, jQuery, XML, HTML5, CSS, MS SQL, NO SQL, MongoDB, PHP, grunt, bootstrap.

01/2010-12/2012

NBC Universal

Los Angeles, California

Developed new web-based application "EventBuilder" to generate event seating charts. EventBuilder allows a user to simply point and click to quickly create an accurate HTML5 SVG seating chart that can be reproduced in a number of different formats.

Environment: C Sharp(C#), Razor, Web Service, ASP.NET, MVC, Framework 4.0, LINQ, JavaScript, AJAX, JSON, XML, jQuery, XML, HTML 5, SVG, Canvas, CSS, DHTMLX 3.5, MS SQL.

01/2008-01/2010

LegalZoom

Los Angeles, California

Developed in-house MVC framework and provided examples and feedback on how to migrate to a standardized Struts environment. for LegalZoom e-commerce (B to C) website. Environment: Classic ASP, C Sharp(C#), WCF, ASP.NET, Web Forms and WinForms Framework 2.0, 3.5, LINQ, JavaScript, AJAX (Telerik, jQuery), PHP, XML, XSLT, XHTML, MS SQL 2008, MY SQL, Windows XP Pro, MVC.

03/2004-12/2007

Disney Studio

Burbank, California

Developed intranet application e-commerce (B to C) BVI TDLS (Trusted Device List System) TDLS. TDLS .Net Web and Web Service application used to manage reservations and maintenance of orders internationally throughout the resort. Also, designed and programmed several components that simplified and standardized data access, exception handling, and security based on corporate requirements.

Environment: C Sharp(C#), WCF, ASP.NET, Web Forms and WinForms Framework 2.0, 3.0 and 3.5, JavaScript, AJAX, XML, XSLT, XHTML, MS SQL 2005, MY SQL, Windows XP Pro.

12/2001-01/2004

Disney Store

Glendale, California

Worked as a Sr. Developer for the HR department, building applications with multiple user security levels while having the application control access to various business modules such as:

- PDF Generation Engine
- XML Data Packet parsing interface.
- Object Validation routines.
- Dynamic generation of multiple web-based forms.

Upgraded to the .NET platform involved the maintenance of several SQL Server 2000 databases while building stored procedures to access data across different database servers.

Used Commerce Server 2002 to develop Disney Store on line. Support of **Hitbox** (web usage statistics) application

Environment: Visual Basic, .NET, C Sharp(C#), ASP, Java Script, VB Script, Cold Fusion 4.5, C Sharp Script, HTML, DHTML, XML, XSLT, XHTML, MS. SQL 2000, Commerce Server 2002, Windows Pro. and Windows NT.

06/1998-12/2001

21st Century Insurance

Woodland Hills, California

Developed insurance Web Pages (dynamic calculator) for California and Arizona clients. *Project:* California and Arizona Coverage Calculator (CACC)

Involved in developing web-based CACC, which allows each client to manage their own Insurance Policy in a database containing common, defined data elements. CACC also can be used to generate reports for comparison of curricula between Californian and Arizona; to analyze trends in price; to identify charging methods. Devoted to specific topics etc.

Environment: Java, JSP, EJB, XML, MQ Series, DOM, JDBC, WebLogic, JRun, Oracle 8i, <u>Jacada</u>, Mainframe, Cold Fusion, Java Script, Solaris and Windows NT.

EDUCATION

University of California (UCLA) Master of Computer Science Westwood, California

CERTIFICATIONS

University of California (UCLA), Westwood, CA

Certification, UCLA Certified Oracle 2000 Developer

Certification, UCLA Certified C# Programming for the Microsoft .Net Platform

Certification, UCLA Certified Java Developer

Learning Tree University (LTU), Thousand Oaks, CA

Certification, LTU Certified C++ Developer

Certification, LTU Certified C Developer

Brainbench, Chantilly, VA

Certification, Brainbench Master Certified Cold Fusion 4.5 Developer

Certification, Brainbench Certified **HTML 4.0 Developer**

Certification, Brainbench Certified JavaScript Developer

Certification, Brainbench Certified MS Visual Basic .NET Developer